Hello everyone. Welcome back.
大家好 欢迎回来
So now we're going to actually start building the network.
现在我们要开始创建网络了
So here we can see the general structure of the network that we're going to build.
这是网络的总体结构 大家可以看看
So we have our inputs, and as I said before this,
输入就像之前说的
we're not actually going to be doing this you know one hot encoding,
我们不打算用独热编码处理
we're going to be passing in integers,
我们要输入的是整数
but so we're going to pass them to this hidden layer which is our embedding layer.
所以我们要把整数传递到这个隐藏层里 也就是嵌入层
And this is just linear neurons so we're not,
这只是线性神经元
you know putting the activation on them at all.
所以我们完全不需用激活函数
They're just linear. And then,
毕竟神经元是线性的 接着
this is going to an output softmax layer.
下一层是 softmax 输出层
So again remember that we're,
记住
we're passing in like some current linear text and then,
我们传递的是现有线性文本
and then target words,
目的是获取目标单词
and so we're going to be trying to predict our target words using this softmax layer.
所以我们要用这个 softmax 层来预测目标单词
Then when we train everything up,
等我们训练好这一切后
what's going to happen is that our,
隐藏层
our hidden layer is going to form these you know
就会形成这些
vector representations of the words that contain some semantic meaning.
包含语义的单词向量表征
And that's, that's what we're really interested in.
而这才是我们真正感兴趣的
We're only, we only really care about these these representations,
我们关心的就只是这些表征而已
that's what we're doing, it's like we're,
这就是我们的目的
we're changing these words into vectors.
我们就是要把单词转为向量
So what that means is that when we're done training we can
也就是说 训练好后
just get rid of this softmax layer,
就可以把这个 softmax 层抛开了
that we don't really like care about it anymore.
我们不用再管这一层了
It's just there to,
这一层的作用
to train up the,
就是训练出
basically like the weight between the inputs and the hidden layer.
输入和隐藏层之间的权重而已
Okay, so the first thing you're going to do here is build the inputs.
所以你要做的第一件事就是创建输入
So here, you're going to create the inputs using tensor flow placeholders.
所以你要用 TensorFlow 占位符来创建输入
So we're going to be passing in integers and
因为我们要传递的是整数
so then you need to set the data type to tf.int32.
所以你得把数据类型设为 tf.int32
And then the batches that we're passing in are going to have random sizes so
因为我们要传递的批次大小随机
you'll need to leave the batch size arbitrary,
所以要将批大小设为随机
so you can just set that to none.
因而设为 none
And then tensor flow will figure it out when you pass in the batches.
这样当你传递批次时 TensorFlow 就会自行处理
And then to make things work later on with some of the code, the labels,
要让代码能实现后面的操作
the targets, this placeholder needs to have
标签 也就是目标 也即占位符
a second dimension that you either set to none or one.
的第二维度应设为 none 或 1
Okay, so that is the input nodes.
这就是输入节点了
So down here we're going to look at our embedding layer.
我们来看下面的嵌入层
So again here you're going to create your embedding layer.
你要在这里创建嵌入层
And so the first thing you do is create the embedding matrix.
首先 创建嵌入矩阵
So this is going to have,
这个矩阵的大小
you know the size of the number of words in your vocabulary,
是词典单词数
by your desired embedding dimensions.
与所需嵌入维数的乘积
So for example if you have 10000 words and you have
比如 你有一万个单词
300 hidden units which is your embedding dimension then the matrix will be 10000 by 300.
三百个隐藏单元 也即嵌入维数 那矩阵大小就是 10000 乘以 300
So then, here you're going to be setting the number of
所以你要在这里设置
embedding features and the embedding dimension and then
嵌入特征数 也即嵌入维数
create the embedding weight matrix here.
然后在这里创建嵌入权重矩阵
So remember that you do this with tf.variable.
记住 要用 tf.variable 来创建
Okay, now to do the actual look up, we use tf.nn.embedding_lookup.
然后用 tf.nn.embedding_lookup 来进行查询
So you can read the documentation here but basically you can pass
你可以浏览一下这里的文献
in the the weight matrix and then you pass in some integer and then it does the look up,
基本上就是相继把权重矩阵和一些整数传递给函数 函数就会进行查询了
or you can pass in a tensor integers and it's going to do the look up on
或者你也可以传递整数张量 这样函数就会查询那些张量
all those tensors and then you get your hidden layer values.
从而得出隐藏层的值
So I'll let you work on this.
剩下的就交给你了
And so here you'll be doing like creating the inputs and creating the embedding layer.
总地来说 你要创建输入和嵌入层
So if you need help with this check out my solution,
如果需要帮助 可以参考我的方案
and I'll have a video with my solution next.
下一个视频我也会对方案进行讲解